CARLA SEVERE

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML5 CSS3
JavaScript jQuery
Bootstrap3 Sass
React Redux
Node.js Express
MySQL Python

EDUCATION

BA ENGLISH & BIOLOGY Tuft University | 2005 - 2009

MA SOCIOLOGY & EDUCATION
Columbia University | 2009 - 2011

CONTACT

P: 404-618-8049

E: carla.severe@gmail.com

ONLINE

WEBSITE: http://css.carlasevere.com./css-portfolio/src/

LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/carla-

GITHUB: github.com/csevere

TWITTER: twitter.com/Carla Severe

ABOUT

Transitioning into the passionate life of a web developer. Desires to use programming skills, along with talents in writing and research, to bring long-term, uplifting transformation to people's lives. Never stops learning. Always striving for growth and uniqueness.

FEATURED PROJECTS

WRITEIT

August 2017

- Repo: https://github.com/csevere/writeIt-react-express
- WriteIT is a productivity tool for writers, offering a variety
 of ways to organize, structure, and plan manuscripts. It also
 incorporates a social networking feature that allows writers
 to share their work and receive or give feedback; aka,
 facebook for writers.

ALIEN BATTLECRAFT

July 2017

- Site: http://alienbattlecraft.carlasevere.com/alien-game/
- Repo: https://github.com/csevere/alien-game
- An interactive dice game in which players must fight aliens that have invaded their spacecraft. Winning requires some strategy and good luck.

FRONTEND PROJECTS

BRAND MULTIPAGE THEME

September 2017

- Site: http://frontendsamples.carlasevere.com/Company_Multi PageTheme/src/
- Repo: https://github.com/csevere/Company_MultiPageTheme
- A responsive, multipage company website with carousels, photo gallery, playable videos, contact forms, and much more.

CARLA SEVERE

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML5 CSS3
JavaScript jQuery
Bootstrap3 Sass
React Redux
Node.js Express
MySQL Python

EDUCATION

BA ENGLISH & BIOLOGY Tuft University | 2005 - 2009

MA SOCIOLOGY & EDUCATION
Columbia University | 2009 - 2011

CONTACT

P: 404-618-8049

E: carla.severe@gmail.com

ONLINE

WEBSITE: http://css.carlasevere.com. /css-portfolio/src/

LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/carla-

GITHUB: github.com/csevere

TWITTER: twitter.com/Carla Severe

BRAND BOOK THEME

September 2017

- Site: http://frontendsamples.carlasevere.com/Company_Book Theme/src/
- Repo: https://github.com/csevere/Company_BookTheme
- A responsive, book promotion website using a smooth scrolling jQuery plugin.

BLOG ADMIN UI

September 2017

- Site: http://frontendsamples.carlasevere.com/BlogAdminUI-/ src/
- Repo: https://github.com/csevere/BlogAdminUI-
- A responsive, multipage administrator dashboard for a blog.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER

DigitalCrafts | Apr 2017 - Aug 2017

- 16-week immersive, full-time learning program
- Covering full stack web development: Python, JavaScript, including Node.js, MySQL, Express, HTML/CSS, and Amazon Web Services

ESL INSTRUCTOR

Boston, Japan, Korea | Sep 2011 - Sep 2016

- Recognized for the ability to develop, improve, and implement curricula that significantly increased students' participation, enthusiasm, and learning skills.
- Ensured opened communication with students and their parents regarding their progress, educational and career needs, along with their short and long-term goals
- Achieved 90-95% satisfaction score in student evaluations.